<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conditional Statements on Zen</title>
    <link>https://itssamuelrowe.github.io/zen-website/conditional-statements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conditional Statements on Zen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://itssamuelrowe.github.io/zen-website/conditional-statements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nested If Statements</title>
      <link>https://itssamuelrowe.github.io/zen-website/conditional-statements/nested-if-statements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itssamuelrowe.github.io/zen-website/conditional-statements/nested-if-statements/</guid>
      <description>You can write any statement under the if and else clauses. In fact, you could write another if statement under them. This is known as nesting. So, if you write an if statement inside another if statement, we call the arrangment as nested if statements.
The if statement written inside another if statement is called the inner if statement.
Similarly, the if statement which contains another if statement is called the outer if statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using If Statements</title>
      <link>https://itssamuelrowe.github.io/zen-website/conditional-statements/using-if-statements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itssamuelrowe.github.io/zen-website/conditional-statements/using-if-statements/</guid>
      <description>The if statement is one of the most important statements in any programming language. The following sections describe the various forms of the if statement in Zen. Basically, the if statement allows your program to branch conditionally. It is a compound statement.
Here is the general form of the if statement.
if condition statement else statement  Here, a statement may be either a simple statement or a compound statement. The condition is any expression that evaluates to a Boolean value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using If-Else-If Ladders</title>
      <link>https://itssamuelrowe.github.io/zen-website/conditional-statements/using-if-else-if-ladders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://itssamuelrowe.github.io/zen-website/conditional-statements/using-if-else-if-ladders/</guid>
      <description>A common programming construct based on a sequence if statements is the if-else-if ladder.
Here is the general form of an if-else-if ladder.
if condition1 statement1 else if condition2 statement2 else if condition3 statement3 else statement4  These ladders are basically a group of nested if statements. The if statements are executed from the top to down. As soon as one of the conditions associated with an if clause is true, then the statement associated with that if clause is executed, and the rest of the ladder is skipped.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>